Dr. Jimmye S. Hillman Papers 1933-2007
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Scholarly Files, 1947-2007; Series III
  - Speeches and Publications, 1946-2007; Subseries I
    - Economic Aspects of Agricultural Irrigation and Irrigation Research in the USA Presentation at Water in the 20th Century West symposium, March 30, 1990 – March 31, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - New Zealand's Agriculture and Trade; Is There Life After the GATT Uruguay Round?, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Del Rickel – Sewer Study, 1990 – 1994 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Agricultural Protection: New Zealand's Changing Role in the GATT, 1990 – 1994 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - New Zealand Fish Study, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - USIA Grant Applications to projects in Portugal and Italy (1 of 2), 1991 – 1992 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - USIA Grant Applications to projects in Portugal and Italy (1 of 2), 1991 – 1992 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - USIA Grant Applications to projects in Portugal and Italy (2 of 2), 1991 – 1992 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Invited Paper – Anaheim, California, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - PECC Speech – Hawaii, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - The Dicey Business of Agricultural Trade Policy: Where Does NAFTA Take Us?, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Forty Years of Arizona Agriculture, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Agriculture in Uruguay Round: A US Perspective, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - The Uruguay Round, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - The Arizona Republic - Agricultural Editorial, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - EC Agricultural Policy for the 21st Century Book Review, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - “Last Thoughts of a Bibliotaph” Article, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Agricultural Policies and International Trade: Where Do We Go from Here?, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Brussels – Italian Trip: Speeches, Meetings, Etc., 1997 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - World Trade Organization Choices’ Article, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Genetically Modified Organisms Speech and Prior Research, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - New Zealand and Australia Speech: Agricultural Protection – Notes and Drafts, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - The Institutes of Agricultural Economic Policy, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Food Safety Issues, Protection, and Trade – Prepared for IARTC, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Genetically Modified Organisms and Technical Barriers to Trade – Preparatory Statement, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Resolving Disputes Over International Biotechnology Regulation and Trade – IARTC, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Trading Biotech: Does Regulation Really Matter? WEA Paper, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Meetings and Trips, 1958-1998; Subseries II
    Arranged in alphabetical order, this subseries is comprised of notes, correspondence, and other various papers related to trips, association, and conference meetings that Dr. Hillman attended over the years.
    - AAEA Meeting - Reno, Nevada, July 28, 1986 – July 30, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - AAEA Organized Symposium - NACFF, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - AAEA Presidential Address Material, 1965 – 1970 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - AAEA Presidential Speech, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on International Trade Project – Regional, March 4, 1975 – March 5, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Ag Summit 88 Conference - Sedona, Arizona, September 30, 1988 – October 2, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Agra Europe Conference - London, England, February 4, 1986 – February 7, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Agra Europe Conference - London, England, February 4, 1986 – February 7, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Agribusiness Conference at the American Graduate School of Management, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Agriculture on the Border: The Present and the Future for Sonora and Arizona Conference, August 29, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science - Workshop on Climate, April 2, 1979 – April 6, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - American National Cattlemen's Association - Denver, November 1974 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Arizona Agribusiness Conference (OPEAD) - Phoenix, Arizona, April 1980 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Arizona Agricultural Outlook 1984, November 28, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Arizona Cattle Growers Association Meeting, August 1980 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Arizona Wool Producers Convention - Flagstaff, Arizona, July 8, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Binational Conference on Mexico's New Role in the International Economic and Political Community, April 21, 1982 – April 23, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Binational Consultation on US-Mexican Agricultural Relations Conference, February 1981 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - British Agricultural Economics Society Meeting – Newcastle, March 27, 1996 – March 30, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - California - Miscellaneous Information, 1978 – 1979 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Confrontation or Negotiation: US Policy and European Agriculture, June 17, 1985 – June 18, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Coordination of Marketing Research Workshop, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Council for Agricultural Science and Technology (CAST) – Updated Report, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - EAAE Congress Meeting – Scotland, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - EC – US Agribusiness Conference - Washington, DC, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - ECSC Regional Conference - Tucson, Arizona, March 20, 1979 – March 22, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - European Agricultural Economics Meeting - "Changing Agri Constituencies in the US and Other Advanced Ag Soc.", August 31, 1987 – September 5, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - European Agricultural Outlook Conference (Outlook 83) - London, England, February 2, 1983 – February 3, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - FAO Conference in Zimbabwe, November 1985 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - FAO Conferences in Rome - Reports of the World Food Security, 1973 – 1979 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Farm and Food Policy Symposium - Kansas City, Missouri, February 22, 1977 – February 24, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Farm Policy Forum – Food and Fiber Policy, 1967 – 1968 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Food and Agricultural Policy Conference at American Enterprise Institute for Public Policy Research, October 2, 1980 – October 3, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Hunger Looking Beyond Famine Conference, October 16, 1985 – October 17, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - IAAE 9th World Congress, Athens, Greece, August 28, 1988 – September 1, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - IAAE History, undated (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - IAAE Meeting - Banff, Alberta, Canada, September 2, 1979 – September 3, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - IATRC, 1990 – 1994 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - IATRC Meeting - Airlie House, Virginia, December 13, 1987 – December 17, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - IATRC Meeting - Berkeley, California, December 17, 1981 - December 19, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - IATRC Meeting - Lake Tahoe, July 23, 1986 – July 26, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - IATRC Meeting - Montreal, Quebec, July 7, 1989 – July 8, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - IATRC Meeting - Ottawa, Ottawa, June 23, 1983 – June 25, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - IATRC Meeting - San Antonio, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - IATRC Meeting - St. Louis, June 24, 1982 – June 25, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - IATRC Meeting - Stanford, December 16, 1984 – December 17, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - IATRC Meeting - Tucson, December 15, 1980 – December 17, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - IATRC Meeting - Tucson, December 15, 1983 – December 17, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - IATRC Meeting - Vancouver, British Columbia, December 16, 1985 – December 18, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - IATRC Meeting - Washington, DC, December 16, 1982 – December 18, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - IATRC Meeting - Washington, DC, June 24, 1981 – June 26, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - IATRC Meeting - Wye Plantation, August 1, 1984 – August 4, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - IATRC Meetings - San Diego, 1992 – 1993 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Idaho Cattle Feeders Association, Inc. Radio Discussion, January 25, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - International Conference on the Unity of the Sciences - "Policy Choices and the World Food Economy", November 26, 1987 – November 29, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Israel-Arizona Business Opportunities Seminar - Phoenix, Arizona, November 1979 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Lisbon Seminar, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Meeting on Agriculture Structure - Houston, Texas, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Mexico-US Workshop on Agricultural Trade, Pricing Policy, and Resources - Santa Fe, New Mexico, August 22, 1983 – August 25, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Monsanto Dialogue Agricultural Policy Project - Regional Forum in Fresno, California, December 11, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - National Public Policy Education Conference - Vail, Colorado, September 15, 1980 – September 19, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - National Public Policy Education Conference, Otter Rock, Oregon, September 1977 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - National Seed Credit Managers Meeting - Phoenix, Arizona, February 9, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - New Jersey Seminar – Notes, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - North American European Union Conference on Agriculture, 1996 – 1998 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - North Carolina Center for Independent Higher Education, Inc. Lecture Series, November 2, 1981 – November 4, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - NTBs Revisited IATRC – Tucson, December 14, 1995 – December 16, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Outlook 87 Conference, February 4, 1987 – February 5, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Policy Research Workshop on Public Agricultural and Food Price and Income Price Research, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Proceedings of an International Symposium, June 1987 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Research in Agricultural Economics and Rural Sociology Conference, February 29, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Research to Meet US and World Food Needs Conference, July 9, 1975 – July 11, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Rocky Mountain Forum on International Issues - Denver Colorado, January 1977 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Southern Ag Workers Conference, Jackson, Florida, February 1, 1971 – February 2, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Symposium honoring Dr. L.W. Pete Dewhirst - Tucson, Arizona, January 28, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - Symposium IATRC Meeting – Tucson, April 17, 1977 – April 20, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Televideo Conference on International Agricultural Trade, March 19, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Trade Disruptions and Trade Negotiations Seminar - Lisbon, Portugal, December 13, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Trade Policy Research Centre, 1972 – 1981 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - United States Agricultural Policy: Foreign and Domestic Conference, January 22, 1968 – January 23, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - University of Hawaii Seminar, July 1988 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - University Religious Council Seminar on the World Food Problem: Can Hunger be Conquered?, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - US – EC Conference - Luxembourg, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - US – EC Conference on Agriculture - Frankfurt, Germany, October 3, 1982 - October 6, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - US - EC Conference on Agriculture - Rome, Italy, December 5, 1984 – December 7, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - US – EC Conference on Agriculture - San Antonio, Texas, October 23, 1985 – October 26, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - US - EC Conference on Agriculture Trade - London, England, November 12, 1986 – November 14, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - US - EC Conference on Agriculture, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - US – EC Conferences - Dublin, Belgium, Ft. Lauderdale, 1986 – 1991 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - WAEA Las Cruces Meeting, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - WAEA Meeting – Honolulu, July 1988 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - WAEA Plenary Session re Mexico – US Agricultural Sectors, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Wageningen Memorandum on the Reform of the European Community's Common Agricultural Policy, May 1973 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Western Regional Task Force on Market Structure and Trade, October 6, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Western States Regional Manpower Advisory Committee, 1967 – 1969 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Wheat Marketing Workshop, February 19, 1969 – February 20, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Winter Meeting of the Allied Social Science Association - Dallas, Texas, December 28, 1984 – December 29, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - World Agricultural Trade Symposium, May 1978 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - World Commodity Markets and the Uruguay Round Conference - University of Nottingham, England, April 23, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - World Food Conference - Brussels, Belgium, April 7, 1988 – April 8, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 25)